Howard Conn papers, 1944-1986.
Congregational Library Archives
Howard Conn papers, 1944-1986.
MS0058
Congregational Library Archives
1.09 Cubic Feet
(1 box)
Howard James Conn was born June 19, 1911 in Fresno California. He attended Fresno High School, followed by Fresno State College and Stanford University where he received is B.A. He studied philosophy at Harvard as a graduate student and then completed his B.D. at Yale University. He served as minister to a number of churches, with the majority of his time devoted to Plymouth Congregational Church in Minneapolis, where he served as Senior Minister from 1944-1976. During his career he held many other positions including President of the Minnesota Council of Churches (1952-1954), Trustee of Carlton College (1948-1972) and Chaplain of the General Council of Congregational Christian Churches (1961). His preaching called upon his background in philosophy and his understanding of contemporary events. He died in the year 2000. This collection contains the printed versions of Howard Conn's Sermons, speeches, and lectures. Additionally it contains some books and periodicals written by Conn, as well as some material from magazines.
Conn, Howard (Howard James), 1911-2000
Plymouth Congregational Church (Minneapolis, Minn.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Reverend Howard Conn in October 1987. No accession number given. Additional Howard Conn materials added to the collection, July 2019, through an internal transfer; accession 2019-16.
Biographical Information
Howard James Conn was born June 19, 1911 in Fresno California. He attended Fresno High School, followed by Fresno State College and Stanford University where he received is B.A. He studied philosophy at Harvard as a graduate student and then completed his B.D. at Yale University. He served as minister to a number of churches, with the majority of his time devoted to Plymouth Congregational Church in Minneapolis, where he served as Senior Minister from 1944-1976. During his career he held many other positions including President of the Minnesota Council of Churches (1952-1954), Trustee of Carlton College (1948-1972) and Chaplain of the General Council of Congregational Christian Churches (1961). His preaching called upon his background in philosophy and his understanding of contemporary events. He died in the year 2000.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the printed versions of Howard Conn's Sermons, speeches, and lectures. Additionally it contains some books and periodicals written by Conn, as well as some material from magazines.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series with each individual series further arranged chronologically. The first series contains published books and a lecture-sermon series all written by Conn. The second series contains sermons written by Conn. The final series contains information related to Plymouth Congregational Church in Minneapolis, where Howard Conn spend a majority of his ministry.
Related Materials
The Howard J. Conn personal papers are kept at the Yale Divinity School archives, under the broad spectrum of "Miscellaneous Personal Papers". Additionally, some of Conn's writing can be found in the Council of Social Action collection, RG0057, under the sub-series "Board of Review-Opposition to CSA".
Church records and registers.; Pastors.; Sermons, American -- 20th century.; Conn, Howard (Howard James), 1911-2000; Plymouth Congregational Church (Minneapolis, Minn.)
- Published literature and the lecture-sermon series, 1944 1975; 1944-1975; 11 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  Contains published books and a few years of the Conn lecture-sermon series.
  - Publications, 1944 1968; 1944, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Symbolism in Stone and Glass, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Hope that Sets Men Free, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Dilemma of Congregationalism, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carl Jung and Modern Man's Search for a Soul, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Teilhard de Chardin and the Phenomenon of Man, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Pilgrim Spirit in the Age of Aquarius, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Life and Thought of Nicolai Berdyaev, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Paul Tillich: Our Human Predicament in its Eternal Dimension, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Abraham J. Heschel: Lyric Adventurer in Biblical Faith, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Plato: The World's Most Influential Thinker, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Sermons, 1944 1986; 1944-1986; 18 Items; (17 folders, 1 microfiche)
  Contains sermons in chronological order, as well as microfiche copies.
  - Sermons, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Microfiche of Sermons, 1945 1986; 1945-1986 (Reel 1)
  - Ten Most Important Events of the Year, 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sermons, 1947 1949; 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sermons, 1950 1953; 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sermons, 1954 1959; 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sermons, 1960 1962; 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sermons, 1963 1964; 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sermons, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sermons, 1965 1967; 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ten Most Important Events of the Year, 1965 1969; 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sermons, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sermons, 1969 1971; 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ten Most Important Events of the Year, 1970 1975; 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sermons, 1972 1973; 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sermons, 1974 1976; 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sermons as interim minister at Bushnell Congregational Church, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sermons and writings, 1982 1986; 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Plymouth Congregational Church, 1950 1982; 1950-1982; 2 Folders
  This series contains records related to the Plymouth Congregational Church and Howard Conn, including dedications, services and reflections.
  - Plymouth Congregational Church in Minneapolis records, 1950 1971; 1950-1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Invitation to Howard Conn 20th anniversary observance, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - An Appreciation of Howard Conn, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Reflections of Reverend Conn's Time at Plymouth Congregational Church, 1976 1982; 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)